Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations
2007-ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
WEB.ARC.003
316 websites
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations, established in 2007 in conjunction with the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS), contains webpages of organizations and other entities concerned with issues related to economic, civil, and social justice from a left and/or progressive perspective. These entities focus on issues ranging from corporate accountability, immigrant rights, unemployment, homelessness, urban justice, healthcare reform, wealth redistribution, and other issues, including a focus on the Occupy Wall Street movement and the Guantanamo Detention Camp. Tamiment also archives political websites, focusing on political parties of the far Left, including Marxists, Communists, Socialists, and Trotskyists. Website contain a variety of formats and materials, including pdfs, images, multimedia, event listings, and blogs.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations, first began by Tamiment in 2007, contains webpages of organizations and other entities concerned with issues related to economic, civil, and social justice from a left and/or progressive perspective. This is an assembled collection, the websites were selected by the archivists. These entities focus on issues ranging from corporate accountability, immigrant rights, unemployment, homelessness, urban justice, healthcare reform, wealth redistribution, and other issues. The collection also contains websites related to environmental and green movements, prisoner rights, the Jewish American Left, peace movements, art and cultural organizations, education and youth movements, animal rights, feminism, housing rights, and other websites related to the Left movement. Tamiment also archives political websites, focusing on Marxian inspired entities, including political parties that identify with or are inspired by Communist, Socialist, or Trotskyist perspectives.
In addition, there is a huge focus in this collection on the Occupy Wall Street Movement, established in September 2011. Occupy Wall Street is a social movement, started in New York City, that works to reform both the private and public sector. The websites in the collection focus on different aspects and working groups of the movement. Another huge focus of the collection contains websites of those critical of U.S. policy in relation to Guantanamo Detention Camp and its representation governing enemy combatants, prisoner interrogation, the related legal processes and issues, the global detention system established by the Bush administration, including efforts to secure civil and human rights for detainees. Contents include prisoners' testimony and documents from attorneys defending them.
These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, message boards (or forums), and audio. These websites often act to document and update upon the organizations' activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their cause or organization, information on projects the organizations are working on, writings and articles by members of the organization or party, or other activities.
The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although Tamiment attempts to archive the entirety of a website, certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (Youtube, Vimeo, or otherwise), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library, New York University began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment continued to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library provides the storage and infrastructure for the project.
Access Restrictions
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after the initial capture.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (including Youtube and Vimeo), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including Twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, Facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Robot txt exclusions also change the formatting of websites from their original display, websites with robot txt exclusions often display as an index.
Keyword and file-type search are also available to archived websites through the Web Archiving Service (WAS). To search for keywords within archived websites, click a site name link in the container list. From that page, click the "search" tab on the top left corner. From the search page, you can search by keyword, URL, and file type across all captures of one site or all the sites in the project.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Websites are selected by archivists and captured through the use of the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS). WAS uses a web crawler to copy the website at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy of the website.
In December 2021, https://reprieve.org/uk/ and https://reprieve.org/us/ were added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.038.
Accruals
In general, crawls of sites are added quarterly. New sites are added to finding aids upon completion of 6 month embargo.
Related Archival Materials
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions
Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations (PE 036)
Existence and Location of Originals
Clicking on the links provided in the container list will take the user to the Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for the website. Sometimes the original website is still available on the live web and the original URL may be available. To get to the original web page, click the live link provided in the "Latest Starting URL" field on the WAS page.
Take Down Policy
Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner's request to remove their website from the collection. To request a site removal, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu
Custodial History
The archived websites were migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The links to California Digital Library were removed in October 2017.
Environmentalism; New York (N.Y.).; Alternative mass media.; Jewish radicals.; Feminism; Civil rights.; Protest movements.; News web sites |z United States.; Communism -- United States.; Housing -- New York (N.Y.); Socialism; Peace movements; Anarchism -- United States.; Web portals.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement); Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- #occupywallstreet Archived Website, Oct 25, 2011- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  Scope and Contents note
  #occupywallstreet is a tumblr blog that contains updates related to the September 17, 2011 occupation of Wall Street by New York City protestors. The website contains news, audiovisual media, and other articles.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Financial sector of the American economy.; Distributive justice.; Social responsibility of business.
- 100 Days to Close Guantánamo and End Torture Archived Website, Aug 2, 2009-Mar 17, 2010; 100 Days to Close Guantanamo & End Torture
  We support President Obama's executive order to close the Guantanamo prison. But it must be closed not just on paper, but in reality. After seven years of detaining hundreds of men without trial, a one year timeline for closing Guantanamo is unacceptable. For the over 70 men currently on hunger strike in Guantanamo, it has been seven years too long. We want justice now. Witness Against Torture announces a campaign to close the U.S. detention facilities at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and end torture and rendition by the U.S. within the first 100 days of the new administration. With Barack Obama taking office, we have a historic opportunity to reverse the disastrous policies of the last eight years.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.; Torture |z United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- 123 Community Space Archived Website, Feb 20, 2009-Jul 7, 2011; 123 Community Space
  123 was a community space in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn that was formed by formed by four grassroots groups - A New World In Our Hearts, Freegan Bike Workshop, Misled Youth Network, NYC Anarchist Black Cross. The organization held daily programs, had a screen-printing studio, a food co-op, a lending library, and support groups. The goal of 123 was to create a community center for the people of Bed-Stuy to organize and make their voices heard. 123 closed down in 2009.
  Anarchism -- New York (State) -- New York.; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions.; Community organization -- New York (N.Y.)
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Spanish Civil War History and Education: Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Archived Website, Feb 8, 2007 - ongoing; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives
  The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) is dedicated to preserving and communicating the history and memory of those Americans who participated in the Spanish Civil War on the Republican side. It is also successor to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. The ALBA archives are housed at the Tamiment Library, New York University. They also publish the quarterly journal, The Volunteer.
- ACORN Archived Website, Nov 20, 2008-Mar 12, 2012; ACORN (Organization)
  The Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN), formed in 1970, was a collection of community-based organizations in the United States that advocated for low- and moderate-income families by working on neighborhood safety, voter registration, health care, affordable housing, and other social issues. In 2010, ACORN filed Chapter 7 liquidation and closed the organization. The organization consisted of 400,000 member families organized into more than 1,200 neighborhood chapters in 110 cities across the country.organizations that are committed to social and economic justice, and won victories on thousands of issues of concern to our members, through direct action, negotiation, legislative advocacy and voter participation. ACORN helps those who have historically been locked out become powerful players in our democratic system.
  Community organization |z United States.
- Act Against Torture Archived Website, Aug 1, 2009-Feb 8, 2010; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp; Act Against Torture.
  Act Against Torture is a coalition of activists based in the San Francisco Bay Area working to abolish torture and indefinite detention, to end U.S. intervention in Iraq and Afghanistan, and to prevent future wars. Our work is guided by radical, systemic analysis of war, torture and detention; the connections between these and other forms of oppression are the reason we support other movements for social justice as an integral part of our mission. We use strategic, campaign-based organizing to link individual actions in pusuit of larger goals. We work to build strong coalitions and are committed to democratic and participatory organizing. Act Against Torture is not affiliated with any party or organization.
  Torture |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.
- Activist Poet's Roundtable with Dennis Brutus | The Socialist Party - USA, Greater NYC Local Archived Website, May 2, 2011; Activist Poets' Roundtable
  Activist Poets' Roundtable with Dennis Brutus was an event in New York City on March 16, 2008. Dennis Brutus was a banned poet and political prisoner on Robben Island with Nelson Mandela and 1000 others before the fall of Apartheid in South Africa.
  Political poetry.
- Act Now to Stop War and End Racism (ANSWER) Archived Website, Aug 17, 2009- ongoing; A.N.S.W.E.R. Coalition
  Act Now to Stop War and End Racism (ANSWER), was formed on September 14, 2001. ANSWER is a coalition of organizations and individuals across the United States, campaigning against US intervention in Latin America, the Carribbean, the Middle East and Asia. Partner organizations have campaigned for civil rights and for social and economic justice for working and poor people inside the United States. They work through direct action, protests, and other forms of demonstration. The website contains news listings, news analysis, information about regional offices, and event listings.
  Social justice -- United States.; Anti-imperialist movements |z United States.; Trotskyism -- United States.
- Act Up New York Archived Website, Dec 7, 2008 - ongoing; ACT UP New York (Organization)
  Act Up NY was founded in New York City in 1987 and is a diverse, non-partisan group of individuals united in anger and committed to direct action to end the AIDS crisis. AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP), founded in New York City in 1987, and is a diverse, non-partisan group committed to direct action to end the AIDS crisis by bringing about legislation, medical research, treatment, and policies to bring an end to the disease. The website has not been updated since 2007.
  Gay liberation movement |z New York (State) |z New York.; AIDS activists -- New York (State) -- New York
- AFT ACTS Archived Website, May 1, 2011- ongoing; Alliance of Charter Teachers and Staff
  The Alliance of Charter Teachers and Staff (ACTS) is community of charter school employees organized by the Federation of Teachers. The alliance works to mobilize charter school employees around issues such as expanding professional development, bettering wages and benefits, improving teaching and learning conditions, and strengthening their voice in school-level decision making.
  Charter schools |z United States.
- Against the Current | Solidarity Archived Website, May 8, 2011-Nov 7, 2012; Solidarity (Organization: U.S.)
  Against the Current is Solidarity-US.org's bi-monthly analytical journal. This capture has not been scheduled for future crawls, future captures will be made only at Solidarity-US.org's main entry here: http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1639kf2j.
  Trotskyism -- United States.; Socialism -- United States -- Periodicals.
- Aisling Irish Community Center Archived Site, Mar 27, 2014-ongoing; Aisling Irish Community Center
  Scope and Content Note
  The Aisling Irish Community Center is located in Yonkers, New York. Established in 1996, the Center serves to assist Irish immigrants moving to the United States. The Aisling Center also provides services for the elderly Irish and Irish-American community in Yonkers and Woodlawn. The website contains event and classes schedules, a photo gallery, and news listings.
  Immigrants -- United States.; Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Irish Americans -- New York (N.Y.)
- Amalgamated Housing Archived Website, Mar 28, 2012 - ongoing; Amalgamated Housing
  Amalgamated Housing Cooperative, founded in 1927, is a limited equity housing cooperative in the Bronx, New York, originally sponsored by the Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union. Their goal is to provide affordable housing and community, while living in accordance with cooperative ideals. The cooperative provides housing for 1500 families. The website contains a photo gallery, an activities committee page, and a community guide.
  Housing, Cooperative.
- American Civil Liberties Union, Accountability for Torture, Restore the Rule of Law, Enhanced Interrogation Techniques, Waterboard Archived Website, July 2009-October 2016; American Civil Liberties Union
  We are finally beginning to learn the full scope of the Bush administration's torture program. Government documents show that hundreds of prisoners were tortured in the custody of the CIA and Department of Defense, some of them killed in the course of interrogations. Justice Department memos show that the torture policies were devised and developed at the highest levels of the Bush administration. The ACLU is committed to restoring the rule of law. We will fight for the disclosure of the torture files that are still secret. We will advocate for the victims of the Bush administration's unlawful policies. We will press Congress to appoint a select committee that can investigate the roots of the torture program and recommend legislative changes to ensure that the abuses of the last eight years are not repeated. And we will advocate for the appointment of an independent prosecutor to examine issues of criminal responsibility.
  Torture |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Moral and ethical aspects -- United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- American Civil Liberties Union, Close Gitmo & End Military Commissions Archived Website, February 2012-October 2016; American Civil Liberties Union
  Close Gitmo and End Military Commissions is a website of the American Civil Liberties union Accountability for Torture Project.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Moral and ethical aspects -- United States.; Torture |z United States.; Human rights |z United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- American Civil Liberties Union, National Security Archived Website, May 2015-ongoing
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Scope and Contents
  Website for the American Civil Liberties Union's National Security Project. The project is dedicated to ensuring that U.S. national security policies and practices are consistent with the Constitution, civil liberties, and human rights. The project is focused on topics such as detention, military commissions, torture, targeted killing, and secrecy. The website also includes links to legal documents.
  Custodial History
  http://www.aclu.org/safefree/index.html and http://www.aclu.org/accountability were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp & War Crimes (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2010, http://www.aclu.org/safefree/index.html redirected to http://www.aclu.org/keep-america-safe-free. In 2012, http://www.aclu.org/keep-america-safe-free redirected to https://www.aclu.org/keep-america-safe-and-free-0. In 2015, http://www.aclu.org/accountability redirected to https://www.aclu.org/feature/accountability-torture/.
  In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
  In 2015, https://www.aclu.org/keep-america-safe-and-free-0 redirected again to the current URL, https://www.aclu.org/issues/national-security/. In 2016, https://www.aclu.org/feature/accountability-torture/ redirected under the host for https://www.aclu.org/issues/national-security/. https://www.aclu.org/issues/national-security/ was added to the web archives in 2018. The accession number associated with this crawl is 2019.090.
- American Civil Liberties Union, Safe and Free Archived Website, July 2009-June 2017; American Civil Liberties Union
  National Security: SAFE AND FREE AT HOME There has never been a more urgent need to preserve fundamental privacy protections and our system of checks and balances than the need we face today, as illegal government spying, provisions of the Patriot Act and government-sponsored torture programs transcend the bounds of law and our most treasured values in the name of national security. Throughout U.S. history "national security" has often been used as a pretext for massive violations of individual rights. The terrorist attacks on Sept. 11 mobilized our country in the fight against terrorism. However, this also launched a serious civil liberties crises. The ACLU continues to challenge policies like the USA Patriot Act, and creates campaigns like Safe and Free.
  Torture |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- American Friends Service Committee Prison Watch Archived Website, Sep 28, 2007-Jul 24, 2009; American Friends Service Committee
  The American Friends Service Committee carries out service, development, social justice, and peace programs throughout the world. Founded by Quakers ( A pacifist Christian denomination) in 1917 to provide conscientious objectors with an opportunity to aid civilian war victims. AFSC's work is based on the Quaker belief in the worth of every person and faith in the power of love to overcome violence and injustice. The organization's mission and achievements won worldwide recognition in 1947 when it accepted the Nobel Peace Prize with the British Friends Service Council on behalf of all Quakers. This is the website for the Prison Watch campaign, which monitored injustices in the American prison system.
  Prisons |z United States.; Prisoners -- Civil rights -- United States.
- American Independent Business Alliance (AMIBA) Archived Website, Jan 8, 2012- ongoing; American Independent Business Alliance
  American Independent Business Alliance, founded in 1997, aids communities to establish and operate an Independent Business Alliance (IBA). An IBA works to build vital local economies based on independent, locally-owned businesses and prevent chain proliferation and other trends from displacing local entrepreneurs. AMIBA provides training and consultation for those wishing to start an IBA.
  Small business -- United States.; Social responsibility of business.
- American Library Association. Social Responsibilities Round Table Archived Website, Nov 24, 2008 - ongoing; American Library Association. Social Responsibilities Roundtable.
  Since 1969, the American Library Association's (ALA) Social Responsibilities Round Table (SRRT) has worked to make the ALA more democratic and establish progressive policies for the ALA and the librarian profession. SRRT maintains task forces, three listservs, and publishes a newsletter.
  Freedom of information.; Librarians -- Political activity -- United States.; Libraries and society.
- Animal Liberation Front Archived Website, Oct 10, 2007-Dec 29, 2011; Animal Liberation Front